（社長）
入社 おめでとうございます
Congratulations on joining the company.
本日は皆さんが新社会人として―
Today, you will all take
your first momentous step
そして 我が社の一員として
記念すべき第一歩を踏み出す日です
as new members of society
and as members of this company...
（烈子(れつこ)）私の名前は烈子
My name is Retsuko.
Now that I've found work
with this company,
都内の企業に就職が決まり
今日から新生活が始まります
my brand new life starts today!
新しい土地 新しい出会い
New places, new people to meet...
私の進む先に輝く
希望あふれる未来
There's a bright future ahead of me,
filled with hopes and dreams!
よーし
これが私の社会人生活 第一歩！
Alright!
This is my first step
as a true member of society!
RAGE
（烈子）ぎゃああああ！
THE BEGINNING OF DESPAIR
♪～
～♪
FIVE YEARS LATER
（目覚ましの音）
会社 行きたくない
I don't wanna go to work.
（目覚ましの音）
10数えたら起きる
I'll count to ten.
10数えたら私は―
After that, I'll be...
模範的な社会人
a model citizen.
１ ２ ３ ４ ５―
One, two, three, four, five,
６ ７ ８ ９ 10
six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
財布持った 定期持った
携帯持った 忘れ物なし！
Got my wallet!
Got my train pass! Got my phone!
That's everything!
忘れた！
No, it wasn't!
（歯ぎしり）
（烈子）うっ…
（豚の鼻息）
うっ！
ああっ…
FOR THOSE WHO WANT A JOB CHANGE
（烈子）ハア…
ん？
あああああっ！
サ… サンダルで来ちゃった
I'm wearing sandals!
This can't be happening.
超ありえない
（烈子）大丈夫
どうせ すぐ制服に着替えるし
Don't panic.
Your work shoes are waiting upstairs.
If I see anyone along the way,
もし 途中で誰かと会ったら
不思議な踊りを踊って―
I'll just do this weird dance
to keep them looking up.
上半身に注意を引きつければ
多分 気付かれない
That should work!
前方にエレベーターホール
The elevator lobby...
あの集団が
いなくなったタイミングで―
Once that group goes...
突入する
I'll rush in.
（角田(つのだ)）
おはようございます 烈子先輩！
Good morning, Retsuko!
（烈子）え～！
つ… 角田さん！
Tsu... Tsunoda?
何ですか？ その動き
What are you doing?
ん？ えーと… 踊ってるだけ
Just dancing!
金曜の飲み会の幹事の件―
Thanks for organizing the party on Friday!
ありがとうございました～
私の仕切り下手のせいで―
That stuff is just not my forte,
先輩に全部
やっていただく形になっちゃって～
so it was nice of you to do it all for me.
思ったんですよ 烈子先輩って…
It made me think...
You're really...
優しくて すてきな人だなあって！
a kind and wonderful person!
（烈子）スルーかよ！
She totally looked!
（烈子）ああ えっと
このサンダル？ バカだよね 私
Oh, these sandals?
I'm such an idiot.
今朝 慌てて家 出たから
うっかり間違えて…
I was in such a rush
this morning that I...
ん？ あれ？
Huh?
また ご一緒してくださ～い
-Let's talk again sometime!
-Hey, wait up!
（烈子）えっ ちょっと！
See you later!
先 行ってま～す ブブッ…
（烈子）ちょっとおおお！
Hey, now!
WOMEN'S CHANGING ROOM
（烈子）フウ…
（烈子）よし
There!
（カバ恵(え)）烈子ちゅわ～ん！
Retsuko!
ねぇ ねぇ このうわさ聞いた？
ここだけの話なんだけど―
Hey, did you hear the rumor?
Don't tell anyone...
So-and-so did such-and-such.
This did that, and it was, like, whoa!
ダレソレがアレしてナニがコレして
ブッワ～みたくなって―
And it was like, bam!
アッソッコがドーンって…
すごくない？ すごくない？
Isn't that amazing? Isn't it?
ていうか
うちのおいっ子の写真 見る？
Anyway, look at my nephew!
ああ～ かわいいですね…
Wow... Very cute...
アッソッコがドーンの感想？
Are you talking about the "bam"?
（烈子）いえ おいっ子さんのほう
No, your nephew.
でっしょ～！ ありがとう～！
Isn't he? Thank you!
（ワラビ田）おはようございます
Good morning.
（カバ恵）おはよう～！
Morning!
ねぇ ねぇ あの話 聞いた？
ここだけの話だけど―
Hey, did you hear the rumor?
Don't tell anyone, but...
ダレソレがアレしてナニがコレして
ブッワ～みたく…
Morning, Retsuko.
（フェネ子(こ)）烈子 おはよう
あっ フェネ子 おはよう
Oh, hi, Fenneko.
朝から疲れたよ
It's morning and I'm tired already.
I just ran into Tsunoda downstairs.
さっき 下で角田さんと会ってさ
角田…
Tsunoda...
私 あの子嫌い
I hate that girl.
Really?
え～
（烈子）うん 私も苦手
I'm not fond of her, either.
私 あの子のアカウント
フォローしてんだけどさ―
I'm following her online, though.
分析の結果
分かったんだよね 周期
Based on my analysis,
there's a pattern here.
周期？
A pattern?
（フェネ子）
あの子がアイドル気取りで―
She uploads photos
as if she's an idol.
ＳＮＳにアップする写真
ほら見て
Take a look.
Selfie, dessert, latte art.
自撮り スイーツ ラテアート
自撮り スイーツ
Selfie, dessert. Selfie, dessert.
Selfie, selfie, her bare thighs.
自撮り 自撮り 生足
She posts a thigh pic
once every 13 days, without fail.
正確に 13日に１度のリズムで
生足 放り込んでくんの
I'll say it again.
もっかい言うね
自撮り スイーツ ラテアート
自撮り スイ…
-Selfie, dessert, latte art. Selfie--
-Yeah, I get it.
あっ もう大丈夫
（フェネ子）
この写真 見せたいのは―
It's not the drink she's showing off here.
ペットボトルじゃなくて
太ももだからね
It's her thighs.
You see?
分かってる？
（烈子）う… うん
（フェネ子）
で 土曜に投稿された写真が生足
She posted a picture
of her legs again on Saturday -
これ いつもの周期より ３日早いの
three days earlier
than her usual pattern.
多分 急に見せたい男が
できたんだと思う
She must have found a man
she wanted to show this to.
金曜の飲み会が
怪しいんだよね
I highly suspect
it was at Friday's office party.
あっ フェネ子先輩
おはようございま～す！
Oh, good morning, Fenneko!
おはよう
Good morning.
あっ 角田 ネイル変えた？
Hey, did you get your nails done?
あっ そうなんですよ
初めて行ったお店なんですけど～
Oh! That's right!
I went to a new place.
（フェネ子）やばい 超かわいい～
Wow. They look really good.
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
（烈子）まあ まあ まあ まあ
Sure, OK, fine.
朝から ちょっと
疲れる職場だけど―
The office is wearing me down already,
これくらいは学生時代でも
よくあったことです
but I went through this
plenty of times in college.
本当の戦場は ここ
私が所属する経理部のオフィス
This is the real battlefield.
My accounting department office!
上司という名のモンスターが
生息する場所
A place where monsters
known as bosses exist.
そして そのモンスターの
頂点に君臨するラスボス―
And ruling at the top of the monsters
is the big boss,
トン部長の居城
Director Ton!
（トン）ぐわあああ うう～！
ふっふっふっふ～
ぐわああ
（トン）ほこりが たまってる
My desk is dusty.
花瓶に花も挿さってねえ
My vase hasn't got any flowers in it!
加湿器の水も入ってねえ！
And the humidifier's empty!
（小宮(こみや)）よければ 私が
加湿器の水を足しましょうか？
Would you like me
to refill the humidifier, sir?
部長のお喉に障りますので～
We can't have your throat
getting irritated, can we?
（トン）フン！ 現在８時57分
あと３分で始業だ！
It's 8:57 now.
Work starts in three minutes.
今日の当番は誰だ！？
Whose turn was it today?
えっと 今日の当番はですね…
It was... let's see...
（フェネ子）烈子
（烈子）ん？
-Retsuko.
-Huh?
Isn't it your turn on Mondays?
あんた 月曜担当じゃなかった？
すみません すぐやります！
Sorry, sir! I'll do it right now!
（トン）あと２分30秒！
You've got two minutes and 30 seconds!
終わりました
I'm all done.
（トン）フン
（烈子）
あの それでは仕事に戻ります
Well, I'll get back to work now.
茶
Tea...
（烈子）はっ？
Huh?
茶
Tea!
はい？
What?
茶をいれろ
Get me... some tea.
これも仕事だ
That's part of your job, too.
女のな！
For the women, that is!
（烈子）んん… んんん！
どうぞ
Here you are.
（トン）おう
（烈子）失礼します
If you'll excuse me...
ほとんど お湯だな
This is basically hot water.
烈子君 いれ直して！
Retsuko, remake it this instant!
ああ いい いい
かわいいもんじゃねえか
Nah, let her go. It's cute, isn't it?
できねえ女はムカつくが―
Incompetent women might be annoying,
できる女よりは まだマシだろ？
ヘへッ ヘへッ ダハハハ…
but they're better than
the competent ones, right?
（トン･小宮）ハハハハハハ…
♪～
Pushing us around when we can't fight back
Neanderthal knuckle-dragging
Chauvinist pig!
Looking at your face just makes me sick
How can any person be such a dick?!
Shitty boss!
（デス烈子の荒い息）
フウ…
10数えたら―
After I count to ten,
私は従順な会社員
I'll be a mild-mannered employee.
（フェネ子）烈子は偉いよ
-I'm impressed, Retsuko.
-Huh?
えっ？
私だったら あの場で
トン部長に ブチ切れてる
I would have flipped my lid
on Director Ton back there.
ああ… でも
ぼけっとしてた私も悪かったし
Yeah, but it was partly my fault
for forgetting.
（フェネ子）何言ってんの
What are you saying?
あいつの身の回りの世話とか
仕事と全く関係ないじゃん
Prettying up his workspace
isn't part of our job.
あれってパワハラで
クビとかにできないの？
Can't you get fired for that
kind of power harassment?
（ハイ田(だ)）申し訳ございません
"My sincerest apologies.
指導を熱心にしすぎました
My style of leadership was too forceful."
とか ごまかされて
よくて左遷ってとこじゃねえの？
He could get away with it
and wouldn't even be demoted.
訴えたほうにだって
リスクはあるし―
You'd be putting more at stake
by reporting it.
そう簡単にはいかねえよ
It's not that easy.
（フェネ子）
ネットで仕入れた知識 おつ
Thanks for the internet wisdom.
わ… 悪いかよ
OK, sure. But isn't work
unreasonable to begin with?
でも そもそも
仕事なんて理不尽なもんだろ？
上司なんて適当に おだてときゃ…
Kissing up to the bosses
just a bit will...
ハイ田は上に こび過ぎ
Haida, you kiss up a lot.
はあ？ 合理的な処世術だろ
What? It's just standard office politics.
（トン）ウへヘへ ハハハハ…
（角田）すご～い
（トン）ハハハハハハ…
Oh, amazing!
（角田）いいなあ ゴルフ
今度 連れてってくださいよ～
I just love golf!
Can I go with you next time?
（トン）
じゃあ 今度 一緒に行くか？
Sure, I don't see why not!
（角田）
わあ 是非お願いします～
Really? I would love to!
チャーシュー麺！
チャーシュー大盛り！
Pork noodles! Extra pork!
（角田）
すごいです～ 超絶やばいです～
Wow, you're just like a pro!
私 何か飲み行こ
（角田）
かっこいいです～
I'm gonna get a drink.
私も
さすがトン部長です～
-Me too.
-Me three.
さすがトン部長です～
俺も
（エレベーターの到着音）
あっ…
Wow... Those two
really have their stuff together.
（フェネ子）ハア… ２人とも
バシッと決まってて すてきだよね
（烈子）うん かっこいい
Yeah. They're cool.
（ハイ田）
マーケティング部のゴリ部長と―
Marketing Director Gori and
the president's secretary, Miss Washimi.
社長秘書の鷲美(わしみ)さんだろ？
２人とも仕事できそうだよな
They both look real talented.
鷲美さんには 社長も
頭が上がらないって
I heard that even the president
is no match for Washimi.
The type of woman Director Ton hates.
（ハイ田）
トン部長が嫌いなタイプの女だな
（ゴリ）ねえ 鷲美
Hey, Washimi, to tell you the truth,
walking this way hurts my back.
正直 この歩き方
超 腰に来るんだけど
（鷲美）ゴリちゃん
会社で弱みを見せたら負けよ
Gori... We must not show
any signs of weakness at the office.
今度 いい整体 紹介する
I know a good chiropractor.
ACCOUNTING DEPARTMENT
（角田）
トン部長～ 実は お願いがあって～
Director Ton,
I have a bit of a favor to ask...
この書類なんですけど～
Could you look over this paperwork?
おっ？ おお おお
分かった 分かった
Huh? Oh, yeah. Sure, sure.
すみません 提出が遅れちゃって～
Sorry I couldn't get this in on time.
心配すんな
Don't sweat it.
I'll make sure it gets done.
俺が ちゃんと
やっといてやるよっと
うしっ そろそろ行くか
Well, should we head back?
行こうか
Yeah, let's go.
暇そうだな
You don't look busy.
これ 処理しとけ
Deal with these.
じゃあ 頼むわ
Thanks, missy!
手伝おっか？
Want me to help?
大丈夫
It's fine.
烈子は偉いなあ
I'm impressed, Retsuko.
（キーボードをたたく音）
（カバ恵）あっら～
Oh, my goodness!
まだ帰れないの？ 大変ね
You're not going home yet? Poor you!
アハハ…
じゃあ 私 保育園に
子ども迎えに行かなきゃだから
Well, I have to go and pick up
my kid from daycare,
バッハハーイ
so bye-bye!
お疲れさまです
See you tomorrow.
ハア…
何か飲もっかな
Maybe I'll get something to drink.
TEA ROOM
My name is Retsuko.
（烈子）私の名前は烈子
Twenty-five years old and single.
25歳 独身
さそり座のＡ型
A Scorpio, blood-type A.
多分 どこにでもいる
ありふれた普通のＯＬ
There are probably tons
of office girls like me out there.
だけど 私には人に言えない―
But I have a secret
that no one can know about.
秘密の趣味がある
KARAOKE
（店員）いらっしゃいませ
お一人様ですか？
Welcome. For one?
♪～
End of the world
Karaoke all alone
Heal all the pain from my office job
Wake up in the morning
And do it all again
Selling my soul
'Cause I'm a corporate slave
Choke on my rage!
（店員）
ご注文の品 お持ちしました
Here's the stuff you ordered.
頼んでませんけど
I didn't order anything.
♪～
Subtitle translation: John Haguewood
～♪